In order to make a collider into a
コライダをトリガーにするには
trigger we simply check the
単にインスペクタ上の
'Is Trigger' checkbox on the component
Is Trigger チェックボックスをクリックする
settings in the inspector.
のみです。
When a collider is a trigger things will
コライダがトリガーであるとき、
no longer bump into it. Instead they will
何かがぶつかるようなことはなくなります。その代わりに
pass through it and this can be detected
通り抜けたうえで
via code.
コードにより判定することができます。
Similar to normal colliders,
通常のコライダと同様に、
events are called when other colliders
トリガー コライダと他のコライダが重なり合っているときは
are overlapping with the trigger collider.
イベントが呼ばれます。
In this example we have a box collider
このサンプルでは
with Is Trigger checked
Is Trigger を有効化してあるボックス コライダがあり、
and a falling 'prop samoflange' ball object.
prop_samoflange オブジェクトが落下しています。
This object enters the trigger,
オブジェクトはトリガーに入り (enter)、
stays as it rolls forward and then exits.
トリガー内に残ったまま (stay) 前方に転がって、そしてトリガーから出ます (exit)。
To check these events we attach a script
これらのイベントをチェックするには、トリガーに
to the trigger, which is registering
スクリプトを追加して、
OnTriggerEnter and logging to the console
OnTriggerEnter を登録してコンソール出力します。
and likewise OnTriggerStay
OnTriggerStay および
and OnTriggerExit.
OnTriggerExit も同様です。
So if we pause the game
このためゲームをポーズしたうえで
and step through one frame at a time,
一フレームずつステップ実行すると
looking at the console will show that the
コンソールをみることで
object enters the trigger
オブジェクトはトリガーに入り、
stays for a number of frames
数フレーム残った後、最終的に
and eventually exits the trigger.
トリガーから出ます。
In the same way as standard collisions,
一般的な衝突と同様に、
one of the two objects must have a rigidbody.
オブジェクトのひとつは Rigidbody がアタッチされてる必要があります。
It's standard practice to make sure that your trigger
トリガー コライダを static オブジェクトとする
colliders are static objects,
ことが一般的な手法です。
meaning they will not be moved by the
言いかえると物理エンジンにより動かされることが
physics engine. So usually you will make
ありません。このため通常はトリガーを作成して
a trigger and then pass a rigidbody
中に Rigidbody を通過させます。
through it. This example is no different.
このサンプルも同様です。
We're passing our rigidbody object
Rigidbody オブジェクトにトリガー ゾーンを
through the trigger zone and detecting
通過させて何かがトリガーに入ると
when something enters that trigger.
検知しています。
So the intention with the trigger collider,
トリガー コライダは
also known as a trigger zone,
トリガー ゾーンとも呼ばれますが、要するに働きとして
is that you can call code without the
ゲームの中で物理的に衝突することなく
objects in your game physically colliding.
コードをコールすることが出来ます。
So for example, with our hoverpad,
例えば、hoverpad では
we can add a force to our samoflange ball
samoflange ボールに力 (Force) を加えて
to give the effect of it hovering
トリガーゾーンに残っているかぎり、
so long as it stays within the trigger zone.
ホバリングの効果を得ることが出来ます。
For example, we could address the object
例えば、現在トリガー内に残る
that's currently staying within the trigger
オブジェクトを見つけるには
because the object that's staying
Collider 型の変数 other に
is saved in a variable called 'other'
どのオブジェクトが残っているかで
of type Collider. We could then address
判断出来ます。次に Rigidbody を見つけて
the rigidbody and add a force
Vector3.up の方向、
in the direction of Vector3.up,
すなわちワールド空間座標の上方向に
a shortcut for 'up' in world coordinates.
力を加えることが出来ます。
We could then multiply by a number
次に後で変数として保存する数字に
which we'll save as a variable.
掛け算します。
And we'll finish out the AddForce
AddForce を終えるにあたって
by choosing acceleration as the mode.
モードは Acceleration を選択します。
Now we'll move our object over the hoverpad
次にオブジェクトを hoverpad の上を移動させて
and we'll use Freeze Position to keep it
Freeze Position を使用して
in the same place in X and Z.
同じ XZ 平面に残すようにします。
Allowing the force of Y to create
Y 方向の力により
the hovering effect.
ホバリング効果を創り出します。
And now if I press play, as you can see
これで Play ボタンを押すと、みてのとおり
as long as it stays within that area
エリアの中ににいるかぎり、
it creates the effect of hovering without
ホバリング効果を創り出して、
having to interact without any part
物体のどの部分とも作用することが
of the geometry.
ありません。 (翻訳:gamesonytablet)